{
    "id": "820e5c327b2841b5ac4b64100dd8aecc",
    "title": "Relative Pronouns Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "There was not a child in the class ……………………… did not weep.",
            "description": "We use who to refer to people.",
            "answers": [
                "who",
                "whom",
                "which"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "8d515858f5494ba7b5b80e9de5576a96"
        },
        {
            "question": "Uneasy lies the head ……………………… wears the crown.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "that",
                "whom",
                "which"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "6059e6ee7a5f44f09ba83fa5fc9f3575"
        },
        {
            "question": "He is a writer ………………………….. I like.",
            "description": "When the relative pronoun is the object of the verb in the relative clause we use whom.",
            "answers": [
                "who",
                "whom",
                "which"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "55e7510f192a4c3f8f5e894a9b4c669d"
        },
        {
            "question": "The house ………………………….. the fire broke out was completely destroyed.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "there",
                "where",
                "which"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "483980eb11074ed78b75675df7c2621c"
        },
        {
            "question": "The reason ……………………………… they parted ways is unclear.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "why",
                "which",
                "that"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "0f1e55147afe4218ae3f8ace81e4b7cc"
        },
        {
            "question": "He is the boy ………………………… won the first prize.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "who",
                "which",
                "whom"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "dea7a33e67c7402c83e6cc9b44fddf72"
        },
        {
            "question": "He released the bird ………………………… flew away at once.",
            "description": "We use which to refer to things, animals, birds etc.",
            "answers": [
                "which",
                "who",
                "whom"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "47a571c118364cb1b13fd1ecf7f000a1"
        },
        {
            "question": "On the day ………………………… he was born, I was the happiest mother in the world.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "which",
                "when",
                "that"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "a2e4a0afc8144e11a453349cdbdffbc0"
        },
        {
            "question": "Give me something ………………………….. I may eat.",
            "description": "That is more common than which after something, anything, everything.",
            "answers": [
                "that",
                "which",
                "what"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "b8113b635ef8437689913e84d0885f92"
        },
        {
            "question": "I have duties …………………………. I must perform.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "that",
                "which",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "abbd56ba3be34bd49bffbc2a111901f0"
        },
        {
            "question": "Childhood is the time ………………………….. the seeds of character are sown.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "when",
                "which",
                "then"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "36a838e3ac334d758226e013afabca9e"
        },
        {
            "question": "You can hardly expect any good work from men …………………………… are great boasters.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "who",
                "whom",
                "which"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "3b2f68d0ca05417089d9b9eb4e45e8c4"
        }
    ]
}